# Christopher M Bergeron

 ♦ Roswell
 Christopher@bergeron.com

 • https://chrisbergeron.com

#### **SUMMARY**

IT Professional with over 25 years of experience including: Cloud, Infrastructure, Virtualization, Systems Administration, Network and DB Administration. Seeking an organization where I can contribute by building new infrastructure and optimizing existing infrastructure, preferably with a career path to a leadership role.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Linux Infrastructure Engineer (DevOps)

#### RentPath

May 2017 - August 2019, Atlanta, GA

- Performed complete migration of on-prem VMWare ESXi to Azure Cloud Infrastructure (multi region) via Terraform.
- Created complete suite of Grafana dashboards for metrics analysis.
- Wrote PHP backend webhooks for various integrations (Catchpoint, Slack, Pingdom).
- Managed day to day operations to maintain the Production Operations infrastructure.
- $\bullet$  Performed DNS and CDN cutovers from CDNetworks / Dynect to Cloudflare.
- Performed deployment of application code to Production environments
- Collaborated with application developers, database admins on troubleshooting and optimizing the infrastructure.

## Linux DevOps Engineer

## **Ionic Security**

June 2016 - March 2017, Atlanta, GA

- Responsible for the entire Production Operations environment in a team structure.
- Performed deployment of application code to all environments: Production, QA, Development, Preview.
- Crafted execution tickets for deployments based on release train / roadmap timelines and change management.
- Collaborated with app developers, database admins on troubleshooting and improving the infrastructure.
- Managed day to day operations to maintain the Production Operations infrastructure.
- Wrote Ansible deployment playbooks for provisioning and infrastructure tuning.
- Worked with the Security Operations Center (SOC) to ensure rapid deployment of security patches.
- Created Emergency Change Control (ECC) tickets.
- Managed VPCs in AWS and GCE clouds.
- Resolved Jira (tickets) from any departments requiring the assistance of Production Operations.

## Senior Linux Systems Administrator 3

# Cogeco Peer 1 Hosting

September 2009 – July 2015, Atlanta, GA

- Promoted to this position in Jun of 2012.
- I am the final escalation point for complex, non-routine technical challenges to our external customers.
- Collaborate closely with SAN, backbone networking and network engineering teams (NOC / NOE).
- Build Redhat Clusters (NFS and Mysql), Mulitpath zoning, SAN / DAS HA storage.
- Work with data center team on configuration management / automation (Kickstart, Windows / Linux builds).
- Maintain internal Yum repositories via RHN subscription.
- Manage Hosted Exchange customer product.
- Train Tier 2 / 3 Engineers in providing customer support, create documentation and training decks.
- Monitor and tune CDN environment (caching nodes).
- Deploy "one off" products / projects when required.

# Director of IT

## **Access Payment Solutions**

June 2005 – December 2007, Atlanta, GA

- Designed and implemented the order entry database system, shipping system, accounting database, and created PHP order system.
- Introduced virtualized servers (using VMWare ESX Server 2) into development and production environments.
- Saved the company hundreds of thousands of dollars annually by re-negotiating long distance call center rates.
- Migrated the entire IT infrastructure from a few 2,000 sq. ft. office suites, into a 50,000 sq. ft building (replete with 300kW Generator, CRACs, FM-200 Fire Suppression, IDFs, MDFs, etc).
- Collaborated with Architects, Contractors, Consultants and Vendors during build-out phase of new facility.
- Collaborated with Operations Managers ensuring building compliance (building code compliance, technology requisition).
- Oversaw Systems (core infrastructure, customer facing sites, etc).
- Built core corporate database Mysql and PHP web interfaces for all departments.
- Installed and configured core LTSP network boot infrastructure for sales agent workstations.
- · Configured all trunks, DNIS/DIDs, hunt groups, extensions and related telephony equipment.

## **SKILLS**

Cloud / VPC: Amazon Web Services AWS EC2 S3, Microsoft Azure, Google GCP GCE, Digital Ocean

Linux: RedHat Enterprise Linux (RHEL / CentOS 8,7,6), Ubuntu, Debian, Linux From Scratch (LFS) 5.1

Containerization: Docker Swarm, LXC, Virtuozzo

Virtualization / Hypervisors: VMWare ESXi 6.5u3, 5.5, 4

Provisioning /Config

Management: Terraform, Ansible, Puppet, AWX, Ansible Tower, Foreman

Databases: Mysql / MariaDB Replication and HA, Influx, Prometheus, Postgres, Cassandra

Programming Languages /

Scripting: Bash, PHP, Javascript, C, Python

Continuous Integration /

Continuous Deployment

(CI/CD): Jenkins, Travis CI

Webservers: nginx, Apache, lighttpd

Security / Authorization: LDAP, Active Directory, FreeIPA IPA, SSH, OpenSSL, Vault (Ansible and Hashicorp), SSO, SAML,

OAUTH2, RADIUS, SEIM, IDS, firewalld, iptables, MFA

Monitoring / Logging: Grafana, Nagios, AlertManager, CheckMK, Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana, syslog, Graphite

Large Datasets / Message

Queues / Memory Caches: Elasticsearch (ELK Stack), Apache Kafka, RabbitMQ, Redis, memcached

Change Control / Ticketing: Git, Github, Gitlab, Subversion, CVS, Jira, RT

High Availability: Load Balancing (L2 and L7), Active/Passive Failover, Clustering (NFS, Percona Mysql, etc)

Network Troubleshooting: tcpdump, Wireshark, snort, Tripwire IDS

DNS / VOIP / Other: Tomcat, bind, dnsmasq, consul, SIP, IAX2

## **EDUCATION / CERTIFICATIONS**

VMWare Data Center Virtualization (VCA) VMWare Sales Professional (VSP)

Credential ID 12075300-9E0A-AF0178626040 Certification number provided upon request

Computer Science Associate Degree

Florida State University • Tallahassee, FL • 1999 Eastern Florida State College • Melbourne, FL • 1996

## **PUBLICATIONS AND MEDIA**

Car PC Hacks (Featured) Geek My Ride (Featured)

By Damien Stolarz • O'Reilly; ISBN 0-596-00871-6 By Auri Rahimzadeh • Wiley & Sons; ISBN 0-7645-7876-6

Release 2.0 Magazine (Interviewed) Slashdot.org (Front Paged)

December 2007 Issue • "Open For Business" https://dashpc.com • April 2004, December 2002, December 2001

## **PROJECTS / MISC**

Linux Automotive Software Platform

DashPC - Dashboard Linux

• Creator and Lead Developer

Dashwerks, Inc.

March 2003 – December 2007

March 2001 - December 2006

Digital Startup and Shutdown Controller - DSSC

• Company Founder, Product Architect, Product Engineer and Product Developer